A Guide to the Louis Arthur Johnson Papers, ca. 1930-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series VII, Photographs
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson greets outstanding soldiers 1949 Sept. 8, Oct. 6, Nov. 10 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Colonel Renfrow promoted to Brigadier General 1949 Sept. 8 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson congratulates Major General Wm. H. Tunner, Commander of the Berlin Airlift 1949 Sept. 12 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Theatre Owners of America Convention 1949 Sept. 15 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Admiral Denfield receives model clipper ship from home state 1949 Sept. 21 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, National Air Council Award presentation to Captain Wm. Davis, Jr. and Capt. Vincent Mazza 1949 Sept. 21 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Secretary of Defense, NAAS Oceana 1949 Sept. 26 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Meeting to discuss Armistice Day Program for Birmingham, Alabama 1949 Sept. 27 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson conveys Truman's congratulations to the Army on Military Government of Germany 1949 Sept. 28 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson's visit on board the U. S. S. "Franklin D. Roosevelt" 1949 Sept. 29 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson and President Truman, looking at a book 1949 Sept. (Box 154)
  - Photograph, North Atlantic Defense Committee holds First Meeting at Pentagon 1949 Oct. 5 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson congratulating Master Sergeant Thomas J. Konopa, USMC, upon his retirement 1949 Oct. 31 (Box 154)
  - Photographs taken at Fort Benning, Georgia The Infantry School, Joint Orientation Conference 1949 Nov. 4-5 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Joint Chiefs of Staff Meeting 1949 Nov. 22 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Johnson at a press conference after arrival at Rhine Main Airbase, Frankfurt, Germany 1949 Nov. 27 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Johnson congratulating Major General Thomas Hayes 1949 Nov. 29 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson at National Airport upon his return from the second North Atlantic Treaty Committee meeting, Paris 1949 Dec. 2 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, President Truman receives first of new Organized Reserve Corps Identification Cards 1949 Dec. 8 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Budget Director Frank Pace, Jr. congratulates Louis Johnson 1949 Dec. 13 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Working Model of the Forrestal Memorial Bust 1939 Dec. 22 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary of the Navy Forrestal broadcasting over WCOA 1949 Dec. 28 (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Louis A. Johnson 1949 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous, of Secretary of Defense Johnson ca. 1949 (Box 155)
  - Photograph pamphlet of Truman's inauguration, "To the Members of Battery D, 129th FA from its former Captain, Harry S. Truman" 1949 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary of Defense Johnson, Gordon Gray, and Romula at the Pentagon office ca. 1949-1950 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous Swearing-In Ceremonies in the Pentagon 1949-1950 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson congratulating newly activated Armed Service Police Department 1950 Jan. 3 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, General Joseph T. McNarney cited 1950 Jan. 6 (Box 155)
  - Photographs of the Great Buddah at Kamakura, Japan 1949 Jan. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, New flag representing the unification of the Armed Forces 1950 Feb. 3 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson greets Japanese delegation of fourteen members of the Japanese Parliament 1950 Feb. 16 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson accepts honorary chairmanship of National Defense Week 1950 Feb. 19 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, President Truman returns from Key West 1950 April 10 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Swearing-in of Frank Pace, Jr. as Secretary of the Army 1950 April 12 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary of the Army Gray retires 1950 April 12 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Retiring Secretary of the Air Force, W. Stuart Symington 1950 April 24 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary of Defense of Mexico cited by Johnson 1950 April 24 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Johnson opens exhibit of photographs depicting equality of opportunity in armed services 1950 April 24 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, President Truman and Secretary Johnson at the Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, Fort Benning, Georgia 1950 April (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Prime Minister of Pakistan visits Secretary of Defense 1950 May 4-Aug. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, First Armed Forces Day Dinner 1950 May 19 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson at Eglin Air Force Base, taken by Justin Rollman, Cincinnati, Ohio 1950 May 22 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson and Deputy Secretary Early lay wreath on grave of former Secretary of Defense Forrestal 1950 May 22 (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson, General Bradley and others at the National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific 1950 May-June (Box 155)
  - Photograph, General Bradley lunches at Commar Club, Guam 1950 June 16 (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson's visit at Haneda AFB, Tokyo, Japan, including photos of MacArthur and Bradley 1950 June 17-24, 26 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Johnson addresses the Industrial College Graduating Class 1950 June 25 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson, President Truman, and Dean Acheson conferring on Korea, Acme Photo 1950 June 26 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Defense Secretary Johnson, Undersecretary of Defense Stephen Early and Army Chief of State, J. Lawton Collins meet at White House on the Korean Crisis 1950 June 27 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Truman addresses Reserve Officers, Washington, D. C. 1950 June 28 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, MacArthur gets U. N. Flag, Tokyo, Japan; General Collins delivers flag 1950 July 10, 15 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Chiefs arrive at Blair House for Korean talks 1950 July 15 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson and Undersecretary of Army, H. S. Alexander examine new Universal hand 1950 July 17 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson meets W. Virginia boys 1950 July 24 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Mr. Melih Esenbel, Charge d'Affairs of the Turkish Embassy visiting Secretary Johnson 1950 Aug. 11 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Ambassador Prince Wan Waithayakon of Thailand visiting Secretary Johnson 1950 Aug. 16 (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Ambassador Joaquin Elizalde of the Philippines conferring with Johnson 1950 Aug. 23 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Ambassador G. P. Jooste of South Africa confers with Secretary Johnson 1950 Aug. 30 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, informal luncheon in Pentagon 1950 Sept. 1 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson as he appeared before the Senate MacArthur Investigating Committee 1951 June 14 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Harold A. Friedman, Rabbi and Louis Johnson, Fairmont, West Virginia 1952 (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Truman Library Inc. members, Dinner, Mayflower Hotel, by A. E. Scott, Reni News photos 1953 June (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Neil McElroy, Secretary of Defense, receiving the good wishes of former secretaries Louis Johnson, Robert Lovett, Charles Wilson 1957 Sept. 17 (Box 155)
  - Photographs of a dinner in honor of Louis Johnson n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Gordon Gray, Nehru, Louis Johnson, and [Walter Tuohy?] n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson attending ship-board ceremonies n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson with various Senators and General Bradley n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous Secretary Johnson with various people (unidentified) n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson and General Omar Bradley at an international meeting n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Louis Johnson with three sailors n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson and President Truman with Forrestal n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Rear Admiral Roscoe H. Hillenkotter, USN n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Rear Admiral Paul F. Lee, USN n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Rear Admiral Joel T. Boone, USN. Lee, USN n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson and Mrs. Johnson at Clarkesburg, West Virginia, airport n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs, Louis Johnson and members of the American Legion n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, Arthur [G?] Barrows n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph of Johnnie Hanes n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson at various meetings and speaking engagements n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Assistant Secretary of Commerce Johnson, and Paul H. Griffith with aides n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph, dedication ceremony, individuals unidentified n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson at an American Legion meeting n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photograph of [Malin] Gray n. d. (Box 155)
  - Photographs of Lockheed's XP-38 airplane n. d. (Box 156)
  - Johnson Photograph Album - Louis Johnson and President Truman in [Indiana] n. d. (Box 156)
- Series VIII, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, mainly re: defense and the American Legion ca. 1930-ca. 1937 (Box 157)
  - Newsclippings and a photograph re: Johnson's appointment as Assistant Secretary of War 1937 (Box 157)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: Johnson, defense, and the American Legion 1937 (Box 157)
  - Newsclippings re: Louis Johnson ca. 1937-ca. 1942 (Box 157)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense ca. 1937-ca. 1938 (Box 157)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense ca. 1937-ca. 1938 (Box 158)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson's defense speech before the New England Council, 2 folders 1938 Nov. (Box 158)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense 1938 (Box 158)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense 1938 (Box 159)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Louis Johnson as Assistant Secretary of War 1938 (Box 159)
  - Newsclippings - General, mainly re: defense and preparedness 1938 (Box 159)
  - Newsclippings - General, mainly re: Johnson's speeches and statements on preparedness and defense 1938 (Box 159)
  - Newsclippings - General, mainly re: Johnson's speeches and statements on preparedness and defense 1938 (Box 160)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense, 2 folders 1938 (Box 160)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's speech at the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia 1939 July (Box 160)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson's Inspection of Defense Plants, California 1939 July (Box 160)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's speech for the American Legion Convention, Williamsport, Pa. 1939 Aug. 10-12 (Box 160)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's address before the Virginia Democrats 1939 Aug. 16-27 (Box 161)
  - Newsclippings re: Louis Johnson's address re: defense at the Lilly Reunion, Flat Top, West Virginia 1939 Aug. 19-20 (Box 161)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson's speech at Uniontown, Pennsylvania 1939 Aug. (Box 161)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense preparations 1939 Aug. (Box 161)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's speech at the West Virginia University and Coal Conferences 1939 Sept. 29-30 (Box 161)
  - Newspaper Clippings - General, mainly re: Johnson's views on defense, 2 folders 1939 (Box 161)
  - Newspaper Clippings - General, mainly re: Johnson's views on defense 1939 (Box 162)
  - Newspaper Clippings - General and Personal, mainly re: Johnson and defense, 2 folders 1939 (Box 162)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense 1939 (Box 162)
  - Newsclippings, mainly editorials re: Johnson and defense 1939 (Box 162)
  - Newsclippings - General, mainly re: Johnson's speeches and statements on preparedness and defense 1939 (Box 163)
  - Newspaper Clippings, mainly re: Louis Johnson and defense, 3 folders 1939 (Box 163)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense, 2 folders 1939 (Box 164)
  - Newsclippings, mainly articles by columnists Hugh Johnson, Joseph Alsop, and Robert Kintner re: the Defense Department 1940 May-June (Box 164)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's speech at the Army Industrial College 1940 June (Box 164)
  - Newsclippings re: Johnson's resignation as Assistant Secretary of War 1940 July (Box 164)
  - Newspaper Clippings re: the Democratic National Convention and Louis Johnson 1940 (Box 164)
  - Newspaper Clippings - General, mainly re: Johnson and defense 1940 (Box 165)
  - Newsclippings, mainly re: Johnson and defense, 2 folders 1940 (Box 165)
  - Miscellaneous newsclippings ca. 1941-1947, n. d. (Box 165)
  - Newsclippings, 2 folders 1949-1950 (Box 165)
  - Newsclippings, 2 folders 1950-1951 (Box 166)
  - Press Clippings re: MacArthur Hearings, by the Senate Committee 1951 June 14-15 (Box 166)
  - Newsclippings, 5 folders 1952-1956 (Box 166)
  - Newsclippings 1958 (Box 166)
  - Newsclippings, 2 folders 1960-1961 (Box 166)
  - Newsclippings, 2 folders 1963 and n. d. (Box 166)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson 1931 May (Box 167)
  - Magazine Clipping re: Louis Johnson 1933 (Box 167)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson, 3 folders 1937-1939 (Box 167)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson 1940 (Box 168)
  - American White Paper by Joseph Alsop and Robert Kintner 1940 (Box 168)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson 1942 (Box 168)
  - Magazine Clipping re: Louis Johnson 1947 (Box 168)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson, 2 folders 1949-1950 (Box 168)
  - Magazine Clippings re: Louis Johnson, 2 folders 1953 and n. d. (Box 168)
- Oversize Items (Box 169)
  - Photographs
    - The Army and Navy Munitions Board, with its executive committee 1937 Oct. (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 2 Photographs, Louis Johnson at the Amon Carter Dinner, Texas 1938 Feb. (Folder #1 & #2)
    - General C. M. Wesson, Johnson, General Benedict Crowell, and Col. N. F. Ramsey 1938 May (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 4 Photographs of Johnson's trip to Alaska 1938 [ca. June] (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 2 Photographs, Vultee-YA-19 1938 Dec. 30 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - Johnson with Matt Warren 1938 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - John S. Brooks Party, Louis Galento Fight, New York 1939 June 28 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - Banquet of M.[ilitary]; O.[order]; W.[orld]; W.[ar]1940 April 6 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 4 Photographs of Johnson being sworn in as Secretary of Defense 1949 March (Folder #1 & #2)
    - The Joint Chiefs of Staff, Admiral Forrest P. Sherman, General Omar N. Bradley, General Hoyt S. Vandenberg, and General J. Lawton Collins 1949 Nov. 22 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 2 Photographs, British Naval Chief calls on Secretary Johnson 1950 April 6 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - Presentation of Inter-Faith in Action gold medal 1950 (Folder #1 & #2)
    - President Roosevelt, Secretary of State Cordell Hull, Undersecretary of State Sumner Welles, and Assistant Secretary of War Louis Johnson n. d. (Folder #1 & #2)
    - 2 photographs of Johnson at a military review n. d. (Folder #1 & #2)
    - Louis Johnson, Omar Bradley, and unidentified officers n. d. (Folder #1 & #2)
  - Cartoons
    - Reproduction (color) of a Bermansky cartoon re: Unification [ca. 1949] (Folder #3)
    - "Truman says Acheson will stay...period," by Jim Berryman [1950] (Folder #3)
    - "One Down; Two to Go," by Carey Orr 1950 Sept. 15 (Folder #3)
    - "Relief Pitcher with a Konstanty Record," by F. O. Alexander 1950 Oct. 2 (Folder #3)
    - "Home Front Casualty," by Herc Ficklen 1950 (Folder #3)
    - "Thrown to the Wolves," by S. J. Ray 1950 (Folder #3)
    - "Casualty List, on the Home Front, too," by Jacob Burck 1950 (Folder #3)
  - Maps
    - 4 Maps of initial concentrations, Germany and Poland 1949 Sept. 1-16 (Folder #4)
    - 11 Maps of the military situation, Western Front 1940 June 5-21 (Folder #4)
    - 2 Maps re: the Defense of America, with 2 charts n. d. (Folder #4)
    - "Polska" by E. Romer; T. Szumanski n. d. (Folder #4)
    - "Finland" n. d. (Folder #4)
  - Charts
    - "Data on Output and Peak Load of Largest Generating and Distributing Systems in North America, 1935-1938" 1939 May 6 (Folder #5)
    - "Data on Generating Rating, Output, Customers and Distribution of Energy of Public Utility Systems" 1939 May 6 (Folder #5)
    - "Measures to be taken by the War Department in the Event a National Emergency is Declared..." ca. 1940 (Folder #5)
    - "Machines and Progress" ca. 1942 (Folder #5)
    - Navy Department-Organizational Directory of Key Personnel 1950 Aug. 15 (Folder #5)
    - Forms for a Synopsis of Situation, Mechanized Weapons Transportation n. d. (Folder #5)
  - Newspapers
    - Four sheets of newspaper clippings from the Moline Daily Dispatch; the Daily Times of Davenport, Iowa; the Davenport Democrat and Leader; and the Rock Island Argus, mainly re: Rock Island arsenal 1938 [June] (Folder #6)
    - Honolulu Star-Bulletin 1950 June 12 (Folder #6)
    - Honolulu Advertiser 1950 June 13 (Folder #6)
    - Honolulu Advertiser 1950 June 13 (Folder #6)
    - Pacific Starts and Stripes 1950 June 19 (Folder #6)
    - Nippon Times 1950 June 19 (Folder #6)
    - Nippon Times 1950 June 20 (Folder #6)
    - Japan News 1950 June 20 (Folder #6)
    - Pacific Stars and Stripes 1950 June 20 (Folder #6)
    - Nippon Times 1950 June 22 (Folder #6)
    - Japanese Newspapers
    - ca. 1950 June (Folder #6)
      - The Sun Pictoral Daily (Folder #6)
      - The Mainichi, six issues (Folder #6)
      - The Ji Ji Shimpo (Folder #6)
      - The Tokyo Times, 2 issues (Folder #6)
      - The Nippon-Yukan (Folder #6)
      - The Sekai Keizai (Folder #6)
      - The Sangyo-Keizai Shinbun, 3 issues (Folder #6)
      - The Yukan Yomiuri, 2 issues (Folder #6)
  - Programs
    - Menu, Dinner given by the Secretary of Defense and Mrs. Johnson in honor of his excellency Jawaharlal Nehru 1949 Oct. 29 (Folder #7)
    - "A Salute to Aviation," Crucible Steel Company of America. n. d. (Folder #7)
  - Blueprint
    - Flying Model, Stinson Junior, West Va. Model Airplane Co., by Gordon Chain n. d. (Folder #7)
  - Scrapbooks
    - "Appointment and Swearing-In of Louis Johnson as Secretary of Defense" 1949 March (Folder #7)
    - "Appointment and Swearing-In of Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson" 1949 March (Folder #7)
    - "Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson" 1949 March-1950 Aug. (Folder #7)
    - "Louis Johnson, Secretary of Defense, Unification, Economy" 1949 March-Aug. (Folder #7)
    - "Special Occasions of Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson" 1949 March-1950 Sept. (Folder #7)
    - "Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson" 1949 April-June, 1951 (Folder #7)
    - "Thirty-first National Legion Convention" 1949 Aug. 29-Sept. 1 (Folder #7)
    - "Armistice Day" 1949 Nov. 11 (Folder #7)
    - "Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson, North Atlantic Treaty" 1949, 1950 (Folder #7)
    - "Cartoons" 1949 (Folder #7)
    - "Final Report, Armed Forces Day 1950 Area One" 1950 (Folder #7)
    - "Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson, Visit to Japan" 1950 June (Folder #7)
    - "Resignation of Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson" 1950 Sept. (Folder #7)
  - Phonograph Records
    - Program of National Broadcasting Company "Magic Key of R. C. A., Army Day," in 10 parts, 78 RPM 1939 April 2 (Folder #7)
      P-463 Parts 1 and 3
      P-464 Parts 2 and 4
      P-465 Parts 5 and 7
      P-466 Parts 6 and 9
      P-467 Parts 8 and 10
    - Speech of Louis Johnson before the National Board of Fire Underwriters, New York, in 7 parts, 78 RPM 1940 May 23 (Folder #7)
      P-468 Parts I-A and III-A
      P-469 Parts II-A and IV-A
      P-470 Parts V-A and VII-A
      P-471 Parts VI-A
    - Speech of Herbert Hoover, in 5 parts, 78 RPM 1940 May 27 (Folder #7)
      P-472 Parts 1 and 3
      P-473 Parts 2 and 4
      P-474 Parts 5
    - Speech of Louis Johnson before the Charleston chamber of Commerce, in 12 parts, 78 RPM 1950 Nov. 16 (Folder #7)
      P-475 Parts 1 and 7
      P-476 Parts 2 and 8
      P-477 Parts 3 and 9
      P-478 Parts 4 and 10
      P-479 Parts 5 and 11
      P-480 Parts 6 and 12
    - Television Talk, General Julius Klein, "The Voice of Robert E. Taft," in 3 parts, 78 RPM 1954 March 25 (Folder #7)
      P-481 Parts I and III
      P-482 Part II
  - Films
    - Col. Louis Johnson takes Oath of Office as Secretary of Defense, 16 MM 1949 March 28 (Folder #7)
    - "Coffee Caucas," with Louis Johnson at the Army and Navy Club 1949 March (Folder #7)
    - Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson, Armed Forces Day Speech, 2 reels, 16 MM 1950 May 20 (Folder #7)
    - Secretary Johnson delivering a speech at the Industrial College of Armed Forces and also at Norfolk, Virginia, on the Korean situation [1950 June 27] (Folder #7)